RAHUL SHAH

Senior Frontend Developer

Address:

Kathmandu, Nepal

Phone:

+977-9808655815

Email:

rahulshah19967@gmail.com

Portfolio Website:

https://rahulshah19967.com.np

Summary

Software Engineer specializing in full-stack development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, PHP, MySQL, jQuery.

Skill Highlights

- Git (Github, Gitlab)
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- Quasar Framework
- Docker
- ExpressJS
- Jest
- EC2
- PHP

- NodeJS
- VueJS
- Vue Test Utils
- Puppeteer
- MySQL
- NuxtJs
- VuetifyJS
- Wordpress
- SQL Server
- Cypress.js

Professional Experience

Senior Frontend Developer - 12/2022 to 06/2024

Orkun Solutions Co., Ltd., Phnom Penh

- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end public a web sites as well as challenging back-end server code.
- Develop project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive user experience.
- Code reviews and merge git commits of junior developers.
- Handling a team of front-end developers to meet client demands and assign responsibilities to developers based on their skills.

Senior Programmer - 07/2022 to 11/2022

Nagaworld Integrated Resort, Phnom Penh

 Getting on board with the tech stack being used for internal applications and website like PHP and wordpress. • Learning Flutter framework and Dart to integrate in house application with wordpress and PHP backend.

Software Engineer- 01/2020 to 06/2022

Aistra Consultancy Co. Ltd., Phnom Penh

- Cron jobs to run regular jobs migrating data from MySQL database to ERP system.
- Use puppeteer headless browser to fetch data for certain tasks where API or DB access is not available.
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end public and internal websites as well as challenging back-end server code.
- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Develop project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- Work with senior developer to manage large, complex design projects for corporate clients.
- Built webapps using Vue.js(with VuetifyJS) and Express.js.
- Helped with hosting static websites and webapps on EC2 servers.

Web Developer, R&D Team- 10/2018 to 12/2020

Primuson Pvt. Ltd., Kathmandu

- Frontend Developer working on a web application developed in VueJS interacting with ExpressJS and MySQL.
- Full Stack development of a website, while incorporating client's requirements using VueJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS and MySQL.
- Received certificate of appreciation for efforts leading to faster product release.

Software Engineer, - 07/2017 to 09/2018

GlobalLogic Pvt. Ltd., Noida

- Worked on multiple projects and made switch from Electronics Engineer to Software Engineer.
- SiriusXM Maintenance: Frontend Development in vanilla JS.
- Telarix Client Services: Got exposure to interconnect business logic and Zendesk.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering: **Electronics and Communication Engineering** – 2013-2017 **Motilal Nehru National Institute of Technology, Allahabad, UP-211004, India.**

Languages

- English
- Nepali
- Hindi